ILGWU. Wilbur Daniels papers, 5780/084
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Wilbur Daniels papers
1937-1987.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union;
Daniels, Wilbur.
5780/084
36.28 cubic feet
35.5 linear feet
Records
Contains records of Wilbur Daniels from his tenure as Director of the Master Agreements Department, Vice President, and Executive Vice President. Includes records relating to General Executive Board meetings, ILGWU conventions, and administrative matters. Files from the Master Agreements Department contain agreements, arbitration cases, bargaining demands, clippings, correspondence, constitution clauses, legal documents, mediation notices, miscellaneous photographs, negotiations, notes, settlements, and wage standards.
5492797
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Wilbur Daniels was born in Detroit in 1922. Daniels held several offices in the ILGWU over more than 40 years, including Research Association and Assistant Director of Research (1943-1950), Associate General Counsel in the Legal Department (1950-1959), Assistant to the President (1959-1961), Director of the Master Agreements Department (1965-1969?), Vice President (1969-1973), and Executive Vice-President (1973-1987). After leaving the ILGWU in 1987, Daniels was Executive Director of the S.H. and Helen R. Scheuer Foundation. He remained involved in New York City civic life, serving on the boards of the Lincoln Center, United Housing Foundation, New York Urban Coalition, and American Arbitration Association. He died in New York City in 1993.
Scope and Contents
Contains records of Wilbur Daniels from his tenure as Director of the Master Agreements Department, Vice President, and Executive Vice President. Includes records relating to General Executive Board meetings, ILGWU conventions, and administrative matters. Files from the Master Agreements Department contain agreements, arbitration cases, bargaining demands, clippings, correspondence, constitution clauses, legal documents, mediation notices, miscellaneous photographs, negotiations, notes, settlements, and wage standards.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/113. ILGWU. Wilbur Daniels papers
5780/155. ILGWU. Wilbur Daniels papers
General
"Permanent deposit"
Arrangement
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Labor unions--Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; Daniels, Wilbur; Daniels, Wilbur, 1923-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5492797
- Series I. General Executive Board, 1965-1987
  - G.E.B., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - G.E.B., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - G.E.B., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - G.E.B., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - G.E.B. National Conference, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - G.E.B., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - G.E.B., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    May, 1969.
  - G.E.B., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    October, 1969.
  - G.E.B. National Conference (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Undated
  - G.E.B., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - G.E.B., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - G.E.B., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    October, 1970.
  - G.E.B., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - G.E.B., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - G.E.B., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    August, 1971.
  - G.E.B., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - G.E.B., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - G.E.B., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    March, 1972.
  - G.E.B., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    June, 1972.
  - G.E.B. National Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - G.E.B., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - G.E.B., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    June, 1973.
  - G.E.B., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    November, 1973.
  - G.E.B., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - G.E.B., 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - G.E.B., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - G.E.B., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - G.E.B., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    re: Beatrice Tam
  - G.E.B., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - G.E.B., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - G.E.B., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    October, 1987.
  - GEB, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    June
  - G.E.B., 1966-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Undated [approx. 1966-78]
- Series II. Convention Files, 1965-1977
  - Conventions. Arrangements, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Conventions. Badges, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Conventions. Banquet, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Conventions. Committees, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Conventions. Convention Contracts, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Conventions. Convention Hall, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Conventions. Credentials, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Conventions. Credentials Committee, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Conventions. Delegates, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Conventions. Delegates Lists, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Conventions. Directives Letters, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Conventions. Elections, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Conventions. Entertainments, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Conventions. Exhibits, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Conventions. Financial, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Conventions. Flowers, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Conventions. Guests, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Conventions. Headquarters, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Conventions. Hotel Reservations, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Conventions. Hotels, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Conventions. Insurance, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Conventions. J.F. Kennedy Busts, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Conventions. Photography, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Conventions. Printed Matter, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Conventions. Printing Orders, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Conventions. Proceedings, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Conventions. Resignations, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Conventions. Schedule, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Conventions. Speakers, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Conventions. Staff, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Conventions. Transportation, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Conventions. Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Conventions. Age 63 to 65 Acknowledgement Form #1, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Conventions. Age 63 to 68 Acknowledgement Form #2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Conventions. Appeals Committee, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Conventions. Arrangements, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Conventions. Badges, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Conventions. Banquets, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Conventions. Committees, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Conventions. Convention Hall, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Conventions. Credentials Committee, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Conventions. Delegates, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conventions. Directives Letters, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Conventions. Elections, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Conventions. Entertainment, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Conventions. Exhibits, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Conventions. Flowers, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Conventions. Guests, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Conventions. Hotel Reservations, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Conventions. Hotels, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Conventions. Matters, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Conventions. Printing Orders, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Conventions. Souvenirs, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Conventions. Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Conventions. Appeals, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Conventions. Arrangements, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Conventions. Arrangements-Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Conventions. Committee Assignments, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Conventions. Clergymen, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Conventions. Committees, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Conventions. Convention Contracts, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Conventions. Convention Hall, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Conventions. Decisions, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Conventions. Delegates Allocations, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Conventions. Delegates Lists, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Conventions. Directives Lists, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Conventions. Elections, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Conventions. Entertainment, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Conventions. Exhibits, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Conventions. Extra Matters, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Conventions. Flowers, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Conventions. Guests, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Conventions. Hotels, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Conventions. Insurance, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Conventions. Policies, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Conventions. Proposals, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Conventions. Souvenirs, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Conventions. Speakers, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Conventions. Staff, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Conventions. Stulberg's Speech, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Conventions. Thank You's, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Conventions. Transportations, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Conventions. Miscellaneous [folder 1 of 2], 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Conventions. Miscellaneous [folder 2 of 2], 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Conventions. Arrangements, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Conventions. Decisions, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Conventions. Insurance, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Conventions. Speakers, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Conventions. Arrangements, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Conventions. Committee Assignments, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Conventions. Committees-Reports,etc., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Conventions. Entertainment; Music, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Conventions. Finance, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Conventions. Flowers, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Conventions. Guests, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Conventions. Notes, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Conventions. Pamphlets, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Conventions. Policies, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Conventions. Proceedings, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Conventions. Publications, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Conventions. Resolutions, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Conventions. Speakers, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Convention, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Convention: NY Reception, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    September 26
  - Convention: Radio City Music Hall, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    September 30
  - Convention: Fashion Show, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    October 1
  - Convention: Theater Night, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Convention: Dinner Dance, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    October 2
  - Convention: Staff Dinner, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    October 3
  - Convention: New York, New York Reception, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Convention Resolutions, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Convention: Paula Green Advertising, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Convention: Planned Communication Services; Film""American Jobs", 1980 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Convention; Total Audio/Visual Services, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Convention: Structural/Display units, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Convention: Entertainment, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Convention: Covers, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Convention: Delegates Guide, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Convention Songs, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Convention: Upper South Department Delegates' Kit, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Convention, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    1 of 4
  - Convention, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Convention, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    3 of 4
  - Convention, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    4 of 4
  - Convention, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    1 of 2
  - Convention, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    2 of 3
  - Convention, 1983 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    3 of 3
  - Convention, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 35)
- Series III. General/Administrative, 1937-1985
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Human Rights and Genocide Treatment, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    correspondence re Genocide Convention Ratification
  - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    correspondence with Howard D. Samuel, Vice-President; ACWA news letters; correspondence re meeting with Senator Jacob Javits re pension legislation; Report on Problem of Low Wage Workers in New York City(NY Urban Coalition); Agreement between ACWA and J. Schoeneman, Inc.; correspondence between Sol Chaikin and President Stulberg re ILGWU work in ACWA shop in North West; routine
  - American Apparel Manufacturers Association(AAMA), 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee address list; New York City Employer Association under contract with ILGWU list; memos re AAMA minimum wage; routine memos
  - American Argo Corporation, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    specialized credit reports
  - AFL-CIO: General, 1976-1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Poll on issues for National Commission on Unemployment Compensation; AFL-CIO Secretary-Treasurer Conference Questionnaire on Frequency of Conventions and Elections and Procedures followed on Nominating and Electing Officers; routine
  - AFL-CIO: Conventions [folder 1 of 2], 1957-1971 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    correspondence re convention arrangements; credential letters; Internal Disputes Plan; Convention Notebook 1963; routine
  - AFL-CIO: Conventions [folder 2 of 2], 1957-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    correspondence re dinner honoring Richard Schwartz and Bill Tatum; re lost ILGWU banner
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards [folder 1 of 5], 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    correspondence re arrangements, guests, winners, etc.; newspaper clippings; routine
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards [folder 2 of 5], 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards [folder 3 of 5], 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards [folder 4 of 5], 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards [folder 5 of 5], 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards. Expenses,etc., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Expenses and Cost Reports and Receipts, etc.
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards. ILGWU Guests, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Guest Lists
  - America's Next Great Designer Awards. Miscellaneous, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Address Lists; Newspaper Clippings; Award and Winner Lists; routine
  - Annual Reports (ILGWU Departments), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Financial Report; Census; Health and Welfare and Retirement, et al; Death Benefit Fund
  - Apparel Industry Statistics, 1947-1974 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Memos from Paul S. Berger re Apparel Industries; Memo from Saul Nimowitz (New York Office of Apparel Industry Planning and Development) re West Side Renewal Project; Statistics re Regional Distribution of Employment in Women's and Children's Garment Industry
  - Associated Sportwear Company, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Agreement with ILGWU 7/1/70-6/30/73
  - Auditing Department, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    1971 Census Report and Comparisons; Memo to Lou Brass re Salary Increases for General Staff and Union Officials; Memo from Lou Brass re Fidelity Claims
  - Boston Joint Board/Welfare Funds, 1964-1969 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Correspondence of Welfare Funds Control Department re monthly collections report, outstanding bills, status, audit bills; routine
  - Brotherhood in Action Building, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Correspondence from Sol C. Chaikin to Louis Rolnick re purchase of Brotherhood in Action Building; re welfare and health benefits
  - Campaign Committee (ILGWU) [folder 1 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Campaign Practices Reports; Copy of Public Law 93-443; Memo from James Lipsig re liability of ILGWU Campaign Committee for income tax on investment and deposit income; Copy of Federal Register June 2, 1975; Report of Reporting requirements Affecting ILGWU Campaign Committee; Memo from Evelyn Dubrow on candidate elections to support; Reports on Richard H. Kuh's District Attorney candidacy; Report of Office of Federal Elections; Campaign Practices Reports; Memos re State Election Laws; Memos re Contributions to State Candidates; Copy of CH.604 of Laws of New York; Contributions requests; correspondence re contribution requests; Memo from Max Zimny re Grand Jury Investigation ILGWU 1968 Campaign Committee; routine
  - Campaign Committee (ILGWU) [folder 2 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Campaign Committee (ILGWU) [folder 3 of 3], 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Census and Census Comparisons, 1969-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Census 1975 vs. 1974 and 1975 vs. 1969; 1973 ILGWU Census Report; Report: Two Locals - Manhattan vs. Outlying Districts Excluding Pressers
  - Central Organization Department (D. Levin), 1965-1971 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Correspondence re Talbott Knitting Mills; report on Central Organization Department to G.E.B; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Correspondence re dress master agreements; Regional Directors; Outstanding Audit bills; IUD-Organizing Program; Draft Proposal-Clothing for the Needy; newspaper clippings; correspondence re Clothing Industry Workmen's Compensation Coverage; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Correspondence re G.E.B. Committees; Dress Negotiation; Maidenform, Inc.; Import Campaign; Bylaws of David Dubinsky Foundation; Bill Draft affecting Tariff Schedules in US; correspondence re Retiree Service Project; tape of radio commercials; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Tribute to Walter Cronkite - 1976 March of Dimes Man of the Year Award; Pamphlet - "The Challenge of Change and Conflict in American Society"; correspondence re 1976 G.E.B. meeting; re Jonathon Logan master agreement; Extract of President Chaikin's Testimony before Trade Subcommittee of Houses of Ways and Means Committee, March 25, 1976 re Tariff Schedules of US
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Correspondence re Resolutions of Canadian Coordinating Conference and actual resolutions; merger of health and welfare funds; imports; Fall 1976 G.E.B. meeting; Anne Klein case; benefit fund provisions in ILGWU agreements; Copy of Northeast Standard agreement and Cloak agreement; Summary of Requirements for Health Fund Contributions, ILGWU Agreements; Draft Statements on Apparel and Textile Imports; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Draft Proposal re Recommended Report, Remittance, and Collection System; Memo re AFL-CIO position on Chiropractice Services; Communications Plan for ILGWU; correspondence re Fall 1976 G.E.B. meeting; cutter's incentives; Supplementary Unemployment Benefits Plan; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Correspondence re Character Foundations; Release-"Inside Labor" by Victor Riesal; Survey re G.E.B. Committees; Puritan Fashions, Inc. from Welfare Funds Control Department; K-Mart; Bobbie Brooks, Inc., 1977 Elections; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Correspondence re Report of Needle Trades Working Group; re ERISA - Southern Labor Union; Newspaper Clippings; correspondence re Gitomer Arbitration; Proposal for Establishment of Sol C. Chaikin Fund at The City College; President's Schedule; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Correspondence from Mario Biaggi (House Representative) re amendment in Public Work Employment Act; Memo re Negro Labor Committee; correspondence with American Jewish Congress; correspondence with Fund for New Priorities in America; correspondence re Trilateral Commission; 1979 negotiations; memo re minimum wages; re Outlander - Leslie Fay; re 1977 Convention; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Trend analysis of Awareness and Attitudes Toward ILGWU and Union Label; correspondence with NAACP; with National Foundation - March of Dimes; New York Insurance Department Report on Malpractice Claims; routine
  - Sol C. Chaikin. President; Secretary-Treasurer, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Deputy Assistant for Intergovernmental Affairs; memo re federal minimum wage; list of members of G.E.B. Committees; memo re G.E.B. Appeal Committee; Minimum Wage Committees for Puerto Rico; correspondence with Bernard Fincastle; routine